Hi, if you're like me, you spent hours scrolling on TikTok or Pinterest looking at Minecraft
building ideas without the intent to ever actually build them. Now, I don't know about you, but
sometimes inspiration just randomly hits. And I have to play Minecraft. Like, that's all that's
on my mind. And lately I've been seeing a whole lot of cottagecore Minecraft content circulating
around the internet, getting a lot of views. And so I downloaded some shaders and launched
Minecraft at like 6 FPS and built this for nostalgia. And if you're like literally any
person who's played Minecraft over the years, these houses were the bomb. They were like move-in ready.
Of course, there was only room for like three things to fit in there. And then there was this
problem. It's Minecraft cottagecore aesthetic because the mushroom houses with this aesthetic
are like next level. They are chef's kiss. They are immaculate. And suddenly your wiki how tutorial
on how to make simple mushroom houses featuring acacia plank flooring are more an aesthetic than
the 2013 mustache trend. And if this strangely specific scenario applies to you, then boy will
you like this tutorial. So now I present three ways to make mushroom houses in Minecraft. Yay.
So the first house is pretty easy. You're going to want to start out with a statistically
impossible mushroom in the middle of a field and use bone meal to make it big. Now stare at that
mushroom until you decide to mutilate it to look aesthetic like this. I wanted the mushroom to look
a bit different than the other simple mushroom houses you typically see. So I went for a more
of a bell shaped curve for the top of the mushroom. You could also use one of those mini water bottles
for reference. I modeled mine based on an upside down flower pot and I think it turned out pretty
good. Once you have achieved maximum upside down flower pot conformity, then you can start modifying
the stem to make it look stalkier. I used the mushroom stem block and smooth quartz stairs,
and if you're in survival you'll probably want to mine a few of the big mushrooms with a silk
touch axe to get the materials for this. I used birch plank flooring to match the rest of the
interior. Now I really like this house but there's not mushroom. Sorry for my sparse sense of humor.
Here's the big grand reveal of this house. Very simple. I give it a 8 out of 10. Next house.
This is a little bit more difficult than the last one and so you're gonna start out by making a
frame that looks like the outline of a handmade cube of play-doh. The kind that the edges never
seem sharp enough. And then start sculpting it to look like the body of this absurdly priced
plastic mini mouse teapot I found on Amazon. I used smooth quartz blocks, slabs, and stairs to
accomplish this. And if you want to use mushroom stem blocks, I'm sure you could, but I just like
quartz because it makes the mushroom stem seem smooth and continuous, sort of like a differentiable
equation. Also because it's not a pain to get all those stems. After this, start making the stem
taller to look almost like a BB-8 and then give the wannabe BB-8 some helicopter blades. These
will be the radius of your circular mushroom cap. Then connect those little helicopter blades to
form a circle. Also, I never really found these graphs useful. I always find them on like TikTok.
But then again, I always just wing it and it doesn't look very circular, so maybe they're
helpful to you. But mine turned out pretty great in the end. Anyway, start outlining the circle in
red mushroom blocks and then be indecisive and then decide on making the easy way out and make
a circular spherical looking mushroom cap. Mine is about six blocks tall and unlike me, you probably
want to make sure there's no weird blocks left exposed. Then I made the door and the window and
outlined them in the most superior wood type, spruce wood. I used planks, fences, and stairs as well as
oak leaves for the window boxes. To add some extra whimsy, you can make a dilapidated cobblestone
chimney and drape that with oak leaves. To add some stuff to the interior, I connected the chimney to
a fireplace furnace type thing and then added an unnecessary amount of bookshelves and leaves
because when in doubt, add oak leaves and bookshelves. That's my motto. Also, I used flower pots,
turtle eggs, and sea pickles for the inside and then I discovered that in 1.16.5, you can place
turtle eggs on flower pots, which is kind of weird. Anywho, I used vines as a ladder to the attic area,
which will be a cute little bedroom. I outlined the roof with spruce wood and then placed some
bookshelves behind them. This would also be a cool enchanting room, but the house demands a bedroom.
So I added in a skylight, which looks good with the shaders and I'm sure it would look good without
them. So this is the finished build. It only took me about 45 minutes to do in creative, so not too bad.
Ta-da!
Right, on to the last one. This one is kind of hard, but not like PryorGaming at the end of his
TikToks kind of hard. You're going to want to start out with a circular base like such and
then add a small circle attached to it. Once you have your two little circle buddies, start making
them taller and rounder. I focused on the bigger circle first because it's going to be the centerpiece
for the build. Also, if this video gets 100 likes, I'll make a video of my little sister following
this tutorial to see how she does because she's bad at building and I'm bad at explaining things.
Okay, back to the tutorial. If you don't know what shape to make the base of the big mushroom,
I referred to the gourd from the 2007 Disney classic, Secret of the Magic Gourd,
and mine turned out pretty alright. Also, I need to know, was anyone else low-key traumatized by
that movie? Because when I first saw that movie, I guess I just thought gourds were strange pumpkins,
so for the longest time, I was fundamentally confused on what gourds were. So anyway, you're
going to start making another one of those helicopter circle things and here's a better
explanation using calculus if you want to know how to make circles in Minecraft. Presenting!
Building circles! Yay! So you're going to want to start out with this sort of graph paper. Just trace
something circular onto it and then fill in the blocks that the circle crosses. Make sure it all
has the same radius and then this is where the calculus comes in. If you look at tangent lines,
you know what tangent lines are, I hope. You probably don't, but the slope of the tangent
line is sort of the slope of if you were to draw the slope through the grid squares of the circle.
This made a lot more sense inside my head, but you can trace pretty much any circle on the graph
paper and repeat this process. Just make sure the radius is the same and that each quadrant
is the same and there you go! You have a circle in Minecraft! Okay, now moving on to our other
little mushroom buddy. You're going to want to make him a wonky little mushroom that sort of
stems off from the big one. It's really hard to explain how I did this, but I would recommend
using organic shapes and have the top of the mushroom thinner than the base. Then add a tiny
little cap for the top of the big mushroom. I basically did the same thing as I did for the
medium tutorial and despite it being vastly bigger, the cap is about the same height. Maybe
even five blocks this time. I kind of wanted to make it sort of sushi like the first build,
but I lost all my brain cells thinking about calculus. If you want the mushroom to be super
cottagecore, you can add some birch leaves that hang like vines and some hanging lanterns.
You could also use shroom lights. I also added a dilapidated chimney to match the vibe.
And then for the interior, I started again by connecting the fireplace to the chimney and built
a loft area with a ladder leading up to it. And then I got distracted by a wandering trader
and quickly resumed my work and I used an absurd amount of birch leaves to decorate.
If you can't tell from my Pinterest page, birch leaves are my favorite.
Also, if you're wondering how they move in the wind, that's the shaders and I use BSL shaders.
As far as I know, they only work for Java edition. I made a little kitchen space in front of one of
the windows, complete with some cake and some turtle eggs, and then added some seating by the
fire. In front of the other window, I made what HGTV calls a breakfast nook, complete with some
plants. While the bedroom space is smaller than the previous build, I think it turned out nicely
and I wouldn't mind living there. After decorating the bedroom, I remembered there was a bunch of
empty space in the loft, which I promptly decorated with barrels because that can be practical when
they're not converting all the villagers to fishers. And I did notice I accidentally made a
sort of shrine to Pinocchio, which is cool I guess. On the outside, I was going for a house-ish
entrance, but I ended up making it more like a hobbit hole with spruce trapdoors and slabs and
stairs. I also added some dark oak for better contrast and ended up expanding the windows
downward because it just looked better. I added some shutters to the bedroom window and shroom
lights to better illuminate it at night. There was something that was still missing though,
and I couldn't decide what to do, so I tried this thing I saw on TikTok where you make mushrooms
out of end rods and mushroom blocks, which I was a bit skeptical of, but I really liked how they
turned out. So yeah, those are three mushroom houses you could easily build in Minecraft.
Comment below which one you'd live in. I know I definitely would pick the second one because of
the skylight, but that's just me. And if you enjoy this content and would like to see more
dollar store green tutorials, please feel free to hit subscribe. See y'all later, bye!